# Luke Floden

# Senior Fullstack Software Engineer

luke.floden@gmail.com • 502-498-7818 • lukefloden.com • linkedin.com/in/luke-floden • Remote US (EST)

#### CAREER SUMMARY & SKILLS

Experience 5 years with startups in the healthcare and sustainability sectors building web apps + leading teams

Practices A/B Testing & Experimentation, Design Systems, Web Performance, Accessibility, TDD Frontend React, Next.js, Svelte, Typescript, Tailwind, TanStack, Redux, React Native, Playwright

Backend Vite, SvelteKit, Node, Laravel, FastAPI, Flask, Pytest, PHPUnit, Pest

Tools AWS, GCP, Sentry, Fly.io, Vercel, Figma, LaunchDarkly, CMS

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cadence OneFive

New York, NY

# Lead Software Engineer

05/2024 - 11/2024

Technologies: Laravel, Livewire, Alpine.js, Vite, Tailwind

- Led development team of 4 across 5 time-zones
  - o Introduced weekly demos with stakeholders, re-aligning a project already a month past its original timeline
- Responsible for site-wide UI design overhaul
  - Adding accessibility features: Loading/focus styles, semantic HTML, keyboard navigation
  - o Increased mobile support by designing for narrow screens and touch friendly interactions.
  - Reduced 1000s of lines of copy-pasted code with a fresh component library
- Upgraded an aging, monolithic codebase
  - Eliminated source of frequent bugs: fixing component lifecycle management with an upgrade to Livewire 3
  - Saved 5+ developer hours weekly by transitioning from Webpack to Vite.
- Introduced automated linting/formatting to front and back end
  - o Surfaced 20+ pages with broken HTML: addressing long-standing UI bugs affecting key partners
  - Reduced time spent on code reviews by reducing lines changed by 50%

# Senior Software Engineer (contract)

02/2024 - 05/2024

- Led redesign of primary user flow
  - o Optimized navigation UX, improving user activation with <100ms response times (INP Core Web Vitals)
  - Brought cohesion to the design system, implementing changes in Figma
- Co-led (with CEO) the process of acquiring a designer: Responsible for connection between design and engineering
- Identified shortcomings of team management and took on lead/PM role with promotion.

Curai Health Palo Alto, CA

Software Engineer III

09/2022 - 06/2023

Technologies: React (Native), TanStack, Redux, FastAPI, Flask

- Developed cross-platform apps with over 20,000 downloads
  - Owned payment/paywall features, driving monetization through A/B testing and rapid iteration
  - Reduced redundant data fetching by 50+% by replacing Redux with TanStack Query
- Designed/implemented external typescript SDK+API
  - Minimally invasive to main product: utilizing cross-document messaging and custom routing

### Software Engineer II

09/2021 - 09/2022

- Designed and Created an authenticated business-partner portal; with instant validation and user feedback
  - Integrated with Slack: aiding growth team in prompt outreach
- Kicked off a project for an external gateway service: managing gradual migration to microservices across 4 development teams
  - O Championed Automated documentation and endpoint data type-safety through FastAPI
- Developed an interactive data analysis tool for machine learning model pipelines (React + dc.js)
  - o Early detection of bias and safeguards surrounding the demographics of our users.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Louisville: J.B. Speed School of Engineering

2021